<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>김형훈의 학습 블로그</title>
<link>https://cryscham123.github.io/posts/01_projects/opic/</link>
<atom:link href="https://cryscham123.github.io/posts/01_projects/opic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>OPIc을 준비해 봅시다</description>
<image>
<url>https://cryscham123.github.io/profile.jpg</url>
<title>김형훈의 학습 블로그</title>
<link>https://cryscham123.github.io/posts/01_projects/opic/</link>
</image>
<generator>quarto-1.5.56</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 15:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>일정 정리</title>
  <link>https://cryscham123.github.io/posts/01_projects/opic/notes/03.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://cryscham123.github.io/img/stat-thumb.jpg" class="post-thumbnail img-fluid"></p>
<ul>
<li>7/16: 오픽노잼 AL 시리즈 마무리</li>
<li>~7/18: 예상 질문 정리
<ul>
<li>부단용 오픽 정리</li>
<li>강지완 오픽 정리</li>
</ul></li>
<li>~7/19:
<ul>
<li>말하기 연습</li>
</ul></li>
<li>7/20:
<ul>
<li>롤플레이 연습</li>
<li>여우 강사 최나영 오픽 모의고사</li>
</ul></li>
<li>7/26: 시험
<ul>
<li>대학연합 오픽</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>



<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> 맨 위로</a> ]]></description>
  <category>영어</category>
  <guid>https://cryscham123.github.io/posts/01_projects/opic/notes/03.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tips</title>
  <link>https://cryscham123.github.io/posts/01_projects/opic/notes/02.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://cryscham123.github.io/img/stat-thumb.jpg" class="post-thumbnail img-fluid"></p>
<section id="smart-전략" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="smart-전략">SMART 전략</h2>
<ul>
<li>S(start by stating your main point/idea): 주제나 요점 먼저 말하기 (main point<sup>1</sup>)</li>
<li>M(mention a few example): 연관된 사례나 예시 제시하여 주제 설명 (body)</li>
<li>A(address why your MP is important by returning to it): MP가 중요한 이유를 설명하며 주제로 돌아와 그 중요성 강조</li>
<li>R(Reflect on what you’ve learned or realized): 배운 점이나 깨달은 점 반영. conclusion 가기 전에 언급</li>
<li>T(tie everything back yo your main point): 모든 내용을 MP에 연결시켜 마무리</li>
</ul>
<p>(억지로 붙여넣네)</p>
</section>
<section id="role-play" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="role-play">Role play</h2>
<section id="section" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section">11</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><p>대충 내용 설명</p></li>
<li><p>첫 번째 질문</p></li>
<li><p>상대방 말 보여주기</p></li>
<li><p>really?</p></li>
<li><p>나를 포함시키기</p></li>
<li><p>두번째 질문 하기</p></li>
<li><p>상대방 말 보여주기</p></li>
<li><p>really?</p></li>
<li><p>나를 포함시키기</p></li>
<li><p>세번째 질문 하기</p></li>
<li><p>상대방 말 보여주기</p></li>
<li><p>나를 포함시키기</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
</section>
<section id="그-외" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="그-외">그 외</h2>
<ul>
<li>한국 고유말 한국말로 쓰면 감점이 있다고 함. 걍 한국말 쓰지 말자.</li>
<li>there’s this []: 어떤 []가 있다.</li>
<li>어려운 표현 쓸거면 비슷한 쉬운 표현도 뒤에 같이 써서 의미를 명확히 전달할 것</li>
<li>and 조심해서 써라</li>
<li>15번은 그냥 스킵해라</li>
<li>you expression 많이 써라</li>
<li>과거 이야기 할 때 main point 먼저 말하고 develope 해라</li>
<li>생각하고 대답하는 척 하기</li>
<li>보통 다른 사람 and i 순. i and 다른 사람은 어색</li>
<li>moreover, furthermore, in addition은 대화에는 어색함</li>
<li>which because really since 로 길게 말할 수 있음</li>
</ul>


</section>


<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> 맨 위로</a><div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">각주</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>What, Feeling, Why Hibit: whenever _↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>영어</category>
  <guid>https://cryscham123.github.io/posts/01_projects/opic/notes/02.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>script 정리</title>
  <link>https://cryscham123.github.io/posts/01_projects/opic/notes/01.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://cryscham123.github.io/img/stat-thumb.jpg" class="post-thumbnail img-fluid"></p>
<section id="자기소개" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="자기소개">자기소개</h2>
<p>Hello Eva. It’s great to see you.</p>
<p>My name is hyunghoon, and I will do my best to answer your questions clearly</p>
<p>So, let’s have a great conversation. I’m ready!”</p>
</section>
<section id="주제" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="주제">주제</h2>
<p>일 경험 없음 학생: 아니요 수강 후 5년 이상 지남</p>
<section id="개인주택이나-아파트에-홀로-거주" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="개인주택이나-아파트에-홀로-거주">개인주택이나 아파트에 홀로 거주</h3>
<p><strong>Q. I would like to know where you live. Describe your house in detail. What does it look like? How many rooms do you have?</strong></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I live in a pretty cozy studio apartment, and I love this place because it feels like my own personal space. It’s not that big, but it’s just the right size for me. I have a small kitchen area, a living room that doubles as my bedroom, and a bathroom. living room에는 안락한 소파와 조명이 있는데, 이곳에 앉아 있으면 편안함을 느낍니다. 이것들이 없었다면 제 집은 정말 단조로웠을 거예요. so, even though it’s small, it has everything I need to feel at home.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><strong>Q. I would like to know where you live. Which is your favorite room at home? What does it look like? What do you mostly do there?</strong></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>You asked about my favorite room. Well, 저는 원룸에 살고 있기 때문에, 제일 좋아한다고 할 수 있는 공간은 거실밖에 없어요. 저는 거실에서 가장 많은 시간을 보냅니다. 거실에는 편안한 소파와 따뜻한 조명이 있어요. I watch movies, read books, and listen to music there. I find this space so comfortable because I’ve filled it with all my favorite things, like a cozy sofa and a nice lamp. For these reasons, it’s truly my favorite part of the house.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><strong>Q. Can you tell me about the household appliances in your house? What is your favorite one among them? Why do you like it most?</strong></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Regarding my household appliances, my favorite is definitely my robot vacuum cleaner. For me, it’s a very important part of my daily life. For example, I can schedule it to clean my apartment automatically while I’m at work, and it always keeps my floor clean without any effort from me. This is really important because it saves me a lot of time and frees me from a chore I really don’t like. So, because of this convenience, it’s my absolute favorite.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><strong>Q. Tell me about the house or apartment you lived in when you were a child. How was it different from the one you live in now? What are the similarities and differences?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>답변 예시:</strong> &gt; Talking about my childhood home, there’s a pretty big difference between it and my current apartment. My childhood home was a large apartment that was always bustling with my family, whereas my current place is a small and quiet studio just for me. I think the most important difference is that my old home was about ‘sharing’ with family, while my current home is about ‘independence’. Reflecting on this, I appreciate both the warmth of my family home and the freedom I have now.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><strong>10. Now, tell me about the problems that happen at your home. What are those problems? Why do they occur? How do people deal with those problems? How do you personally deal with those problems?</strong></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>The biggest problem I’ve ever had at home was when my air conditioner broke down during a really hot summer. The main issue was that my apartment became like an oven, which was a big deal because I couldn’t sleep or even relax. To deal with this problem, I had to call a repairman, but I had to wait for a few days because they were so busy. During that time, I spent most of my days at nearby cafes to escape the heat. This whole experience taught me that it’s very important to check my appliances before the season starts.</p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="영화공연콘서트음악" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="영화공연콘서트음악">영화/공연/콘서트/음악</h3>
<p><strong>Q1. What is your favorite genre of movies? Why do you like those types of movies?</strong> (당신이 좋아하는 영화 장르는 무엇인가요? 왜 그 장르를 좋아하나요?)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>That’s an interesting question. While I enjoy many genres, my absolute favorite type of movie these days is <strong>music films, especially live concert films.</strong> The reason is simple: they combine the best of both worlds. You get the immersive sound and giant screen of a movie theater, but you also get to feel the incredible energy and passion of a live concert. It’s a very powerful and emotional experience for me, and I find it’s the best way to really appreciate an artist’s performance.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><strong>Q2. I’d like you to tell me about one of the most memorable movies you’ve seen.</strong> (당신이 본 영화 중 가장 기억에 남는 영화는 무엇인가요?)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>The most memorable movie I’ve ever seen was actually a concert film called <strong>‘Coldplay: Music of the Spheres’.</strong> I’m a huge fan of Coldplay, but I couldn’t get tickets to their actual show in my country. So when I heard it was broadcasting live in theaters, I went to see it immediately. The sound quality in the theater was just amazing, and seeing the artists’ expressions up close on a huge screen was incredible. The most special part was that everyone in the audience was singing and dancing together, almost like a real concert. It truly showed me a whole new way to enjoy music.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><strong>Q3. Tell me about a time when you went to listen to some live music.</strong> (라이브 음악을 들으러 갔을 때에 대해 말해주세요.)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>You asked about a time I went to listen to live music. Well, one of the most unique live music experiences I’ve had was, interestingly, <strong>at a movie theater.</strong> I went to see a live broadcast of a Coldplay concert. The mood in the theater was electric. Even though we were in our cinema seats, people were standing up, singing along to every song, and waving light sticks. The music itself was fantastic, of course, but what made it so special was sharing that “live” energy with all the other fans in the same space. It was a very powerful and modern way to enjoy a live performance.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><strong>Q4. Could you compare the movies made today to movies you saw while you were growing up?</strong> (요즘 영화와 당신이 자라날 때 보았던 영화를 비교해주세요.)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I think the biggest difference between movies today and movies from the past is the <strong>technology and the variety of content.</strong> Of course, today’s movies have amazing special effects and sound systems, which makes everything more realistic and immersive. But more importantly, the <em>type</em> of content has expanded. When I was young, a movie was usually just a fictional story. But now, as I’ve mentioned, we can watch live concerts, musicals, and even operas in the movie theater. This kind of “alternative content” was almost unimaginable in the past. So I would say movies have become a much broader entertainment platform.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><strong>Q5. How have the performances in your country changed or developed over the last several years?</strong> (지난 몇 년간 당신의 나라의 공연들은 어떻게 변해왔나요?)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>In my opinion, the biggest change in how people enjoy performances in Korea is how <strong>technology has made them much more accessible.</strong> In the past, you had to physically be at the concert hall or theater, and getting a ticket was often very competitive. But now, things have changed a lot. Many popular concerts and musicals are <strong>broadcast live in movie theaters</strong> nationwide. I think this is a fantastic development because it allows more people to enjoy high-quality performances, even if they live far away or couldn’t get a ticket. It has really opened up a new market and a new way for people to experience culture.</p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="공원가기-캠핑하기" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="공원가기-캠핑하기">공원가기 캠핑하기</h3>
<p><strong>Q1. You indicated that you like to go to parks. Tell me about one of the parks that you often visit. What does it look like?</strong> (자주 가는 공원에 대해 말해주세요. 어떻게 생겼나요?)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Sure. One of the parks I love to visit is <strong>Nanji Hangang Park</strong>, located right next to the Han River in Seoul. It’s a huge, open park with a lot of green grass, which is perfect for picnics or just relaxing. Many people ride bikes along the river or fly kites on windy days. But what makes this park truly special for me is that it has a large, well-equipped camping site inside. It’s not every day you find a place where you can enjoy both a regular park atmosphere and a real camping experience right in the middle of the city.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><strong>Q2. Tell the place you usually go camping. What does it look like? Why do you like to go there?</strong> (자주 캠핑가는 장소에 대해 말해주세요. 왜 그곳을 좋아하나요?)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>My go-to place for camping is, as I just mentioned, the <strong>Nanji Camping Site</strong> inside Hangang Park. It’s the perfect combination of nature and convenience. The campsite itself is a large grassy area with designated spots where you can park your car right next to your tent. It has clean public restrooms and even a convenience store, which is amazing. I love going there because I can enjoy an outdoor barbecue and a real camping vibe without having to drive for hours out of the city. It’s the easiest way to escape from my daily routine.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><strong>Q3. Do you have any memorable experience when you went camping? When was it? Who did you go with? What happened?</strong> (캠핑을 갔을 때 기억에 남는 경험이 있나요?)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>My most memorable camping experience was actually my first time going <strong>solo camping</strong>, and it was at Nanji Camping Site last fall. I wanted to have some time to myself and clear my head. To be honest, I struggled a bit to set up my new tent all by myself. But after I finally did, I was sitting in my chair, enjoying a cup of coffee and watching the beautiful sunset over the river. Suddenly, it started to rain really hard. At first, I was worried it would ruin my trip, but I went inside my tent. Listening to the sound of the rain hitting the tent was incredibly peaceful and cozy. It turned a potentially bad situation into a very calm and special memory.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><strong>Q4. I would like to know things you usually bring when you go camping. Why do you take those?</strong> (캠핑갈 때 주로 가져가는 것들에 대해 말해주세요.)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>When I go camping, I have a few essential items I always bring. I would group them into three categories. First is for <strong>shelter</strong>, so of course, I bring my tent, a comfortable sleeping bag, and a thick mat to put underneath it. Next is for <strong>comfort</strong>. For this, I always take a foldable chair and a small table. They are important because sitting on a chair is much more comfortable than sitting on the ground. Lastly, and most importantly, is for <strong>food</strong>. I bring a portable gas stove and a cooler box filled with food. These items are essential because having a delicious barbecue is one of the biggest joys of camping for me.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><strong>Q5. Tell me about your most memorable experience that have happened at the park.</strong> (공원에서 발생했던 당신의 가장 기억에 남는 경험에 대해 말해주세요.)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>My most memorable experience at a park actually happened while I was <strong>camping at Nanji Hangang Park</strong>. As I mentioned, I was on my first-ever solo camping trip there. After setting up my tent, I was just enjoying the park’s general atmosphere, watching people walk by and seeing the sunset over the river. But then, a sudden summer rain began to pour. Instead of ruining my day at the park, it actually made it more special. I sat inside my tent, listening to the rain and feeling very cozy and close to nature. It was a really peaceful moment that I’ll never forget, all thanks to that park. <em>(<strong>Note:</strong> 3번 캠핑 경험과 동일한 이야기를, ’공원에서 있었던 일’이라는 관점으로 살짝 바꾸어 답변하는 전략입니다. 매우 효율적입니다.)</em></p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="조깅-걷기-운동을-전혀-하지-않음" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="조깅-걷기-운동을-전혀-하지-않음">조깅 걷기 운동을 전혀 하지 않음</h3>
</section>
<section id="집에서-보내는-휴가" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="집에서-보내는-휴가">집에서 보내는 휴가</h3>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb1" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode python code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode python"><span id="cb1-1">Q. Most people want to travel during vacations. Tell me why you prefer staying at home. What makes your vacation at home enjoyable? </span>
<span id="cb1-2">대부분의 사람들이 휴가기간에 여행가는 것을 원합니다. 당신이 집에 머물러있는 걸 더 좋아하는 이유를 말해주세요. 어떤게 집에서 보내는 휴가를 즐겁게 만드나요?</span>
<span id="cb1-3"> </span>
<span id="cb1-4"> </span>
<span id="cb1-5">Q. You indicated <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">in</span> the survey that you take vacations at home. Who do you meet when you have vacations at home? What do you do <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">with</span> them? Give me specific examples.</span>
<span id="cb1-6">당신은 집에서 휴가를 보낸다고 말했습니다. 집에서 휴가를 보낼 때 누구를 만나나요? 그들과 함께 무엇을 하나요? 상세한 예시와 함께 설명해주세요</span>
<span id="cb1-7"> </span>
<span id="cb1-8"> </span>
<span id="cb1-9">Q. I would like to know about the memorable vacation you have spent at home. What did you do <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">and</span> who were you <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">with</span>? Why was it so memorable?</span>
<span id="cb1-10">당신이 집에서 보낸 휴가중 기억에 남는 휴가에 대해 알고싶어요. 언제 누구와 함께 휴가를 보냈나요? 왜 그 휴가가 기억에 남나요?</span>
<span id="cb1-11"> </span>
<span id="cb1-12"> </span>
<span id="cb1-13">Q. Describe what you did during last vacation that you spent at home. Give me a description of first to the last day of everything tyou did.</span>
<span id="cb1-14">당신이 집에서 보낸 마지막 휴가에 대해 묘사해주세요. 당신이 했던 일에 대해 첫날부터 마지막 날까지 모두 묘사해주세요.</span>
<span id="cb1-15"> </span>
<span id="cb1-16"> </span>
<span id="cb1-17">Q. You indicated that you take vacations at home. What do people normally do on their vacations? How has the way they spend vacations changed over the years? </span>
<span id="cb1-18">당신은 집에서 휴가를 보낸다고했습니다. 사람들이 보통 휴가 때 무엇을 하나요? 사람들이 휴가를 보내는 방식은 시간이 지나면서 어떻게 변해왔나요? </span>
<span id="cb1-19"> </span>
<span id="cb1-20"> </span>
<span id="cb1-21">Q. Why do you think people need vacations? What purposes do you think vacations have <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">for</span> different people?</span>
<span id="cb1-22">당신은 사람들에게 왜 휴가가 필요하다고 생각하나요? 사람들이 휴가를 가는 목적은 무엇일까요?</span>
<span id="cb1-23"> </span>
<span id="cb1-24"> </span>
<span id="cb1-25">Q. Experts state that vacation <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">is</span> important <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">for</span> one<span class="st" style="color: #20794D;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">'s health and relationships with others. Take a minute to discuss your view on how important vacations are.</span></span>
<span id="cb1-26"><span class="er" style="color: #AD0000;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">전문가들은 휴가가 개인의 건강과 대인관계에 있어 중요하다고 말합니다. 휴가의 중요성에 대한 당신의 생각을 말해보세요.</span></span></code></pre></div>
</section>
<section id="국내여행-해외여행" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="국내여행-해외여행">국내여행 해외여행</h3>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb2" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode python code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode python"><span id="cb2-1">Q. What are some things that you do to prepare <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">for</span> trips?</span>
<span id="cb2-2">여행을 준비할 때 당신이 하는 일들은 무엇인가요?</span>
<span id="cb2-3"> </span>
<span id="cb2-4"> </span>
<span id="cb2-5">Q. You indicated that you enjoy domestic travel. Where do you like to visit? Describe the place you would like to visit <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">and</span> why you love to go there.</span>
<span id="cb2-6">사전 설문에서 당신은 국내 여행을 즐긴다고 답했습니다. 당신은 어디를 좋아하나요?  어느 곳을 가고싶은지, 왜 그곳을 좋아하는지 설명해주세요.</span>
<span id="cb2-7"> </span>
<span id="cb2-8"> </span>
<span id="cb2-9">Q. When people think about traveling to foreign countries, what are some things they are most interested <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">in</span>? Why do you think these things are of such interest to travelers?</span>
<span id="cb2-10">사람들이 외국 여행을 간다고 생각할 때 그들이 흥미를 느끼는 것은 무엇일까요? 이러한 것들이 관광객들에게 흥미로운 이유는 무엇일까요?</span>
<span id="cb2-11"> </span>
<span id="cb2-12"> </span>
<span id="cb2-13">Q. Unexpected things can happen <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">while</span> you are traveling. Talk about an unforgettable happening on a trip. Why was the experience so memorable? </span>
<span id="cb2-14">여행을 할 땐 예상치 못한 일이 벌어지기도 합니다. 당신이 여행 중 겪은 잊지 못할 일에 대해 말해주세요. 왜 그 경험이 기억에 남나요? </span>
<span id="cb2-15"> </span>
<span id="cb2-16"> </span>
<span id="cb2-17">Q. Tell me about a foreign country you visited when you were young. What was special? What do you remember?</span>
<span id="cb2-18">당신이 어렸을 때 방문했던 외국에 대해 말해주세요. 무엇이 특별했나요? 어떤게 기억에 남나요?</span>
<span id="cb2-19"> </span>
<span id="cb2-20"> </span>
<span id="cb2-21">Q. Talk about a trip you went <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">in</span> your childhood. What do you remember about that trip? Where did you go, <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">and</span> whom did you go <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">with</span>? </span>
<span id="cb2-22">당신이 어릴 적에 갔던 여행에 대해 말해주세요. 그 여행에 대해 기억나는 건 뭔가요? 언제 누구와 함께 여행을 갔었나요? </span>
<span id="cb2-23"> </span>
<span id="cb2-24"> </span>
<span id="cb2-25">Q. Can you describe <span class="cf" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">for</span> me some of the things that you enjoy doing on your vacation?</span>
<span id="cb2-26">당신이 휴가를 가있는 동안 즐기는 것들에 대해 묘사해줄 수 있나요?</span>
<span id="cb2-27"> </span>
<span id="cb2-28"> </span>
<span id="cb2-29">Q, Tell me about where tourists go <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">and</span> what they do on their overseas trip. Give me <span class="bu" style="color: null;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">all</span> the details.</span>
<span id="cb2-30">관광객들이 가는 여행지와 그곳에서 하는 일애 해 얘기해주세요. 너에게 그것에 대해 자세하게 말해주세요</span>
<span id="cb2-31"> </span>
<span id="cb2-32"> </span>
<span id="cb2-33">Q. Tell me a story that you experienced when teaveling overseas. What happened <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-weight: bold;
font-style: inherit;">and</span> what made that incident memorable?</span>
<span id="cb2-34">당신의 해외여행 경험에  대해 얘기해주세요. 어떤 일이 일어났고 무엇이 그걸 기억에 남게 했나요?</span></code></pre></div>


</section>
</section>

<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> 맨 위로</a> ]]></description>
  <category>영어</category>
  <guid>https://cryscham123.github.io/posts/01_projects/opic/notes/01.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>오픽 구조 파악</title>
  <link>https://cryscham123.github.io/posts/01_projects/opic/notes/00.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://cryscham123.github.io/img/stat-thumb.jpg" class="post-thumbnail img-fluid"></p>
<section id="시험-구조" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="시험-구조">시험 구조</h2>
<ul>
<li>시험 시간은 총 40분. 답변 시간은 자유</li>
<li>2분 정도 지나면 다음 문제로 넘어갈 수 있는 버튼이 활성화됨.</li>
<li>후반 문제는 조금 늦게 나옴</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="질문-유형" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="질문-유형">질문 유형</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>자기소개</li>
<li>background survey</li>
<li>돌발</li>
</ol>
<p>1번 문제가 자기소개. 점수엔 딱히 영향 없고, 그냥 목소리 푸는 용도</p>
<p>2/3/4, 5/6/7, 8/9/10, 11/12/13, 14/15 는 background survey 및 돌발 질문</p>
<p>각각의 묶음은 combo 문제</p>
<section id="combo-별-10개-유형" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="combo-별-10개-유형">combo 별 10개 유형</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>묘사
<ul>
<li>일반적으로 이렇다는걸 대답. 현재형으로 대답</li>
<li>가장 쉽고 배점이 낮기 때문에 적당히 대답</li>
</ul></li>
<li>루틴, 단계, 활동
<ul>
<li>1번과 마찬가지로 현재형으로 대답</li>
</ul></li>
<li>처음 / 최근 경험
<ul>
<li>육하원칙, 과거형</li>
<li>최초 경험은 시간에 따른 취향 변화도 물어봄</li>
</ul></li>
<li>가장 인상적인 경험
<ul>
<li>구체적인 설명 필요. 문제 경험을 물어보기도 함</li>
<li>배점이 높으니까 신경써서 대답</li>
</ul></li>
<li>에바에게 질문하기
<ul>
<li>안나옴</li>
</ul></li>
<li>주어진 상황에 3-4가지 정보 요청하기</li>
<li>6번에서의 문제 상황 설명 및 대책 2-3가지 세우기</li>
<li>이와 같은 본인 경험
<ul>
<li>7번과 유사한 나의 경험</li>
</ul></li>
<li>비교 / 대조
<ul>
<li>자세한 예를 들어 설명</li>
<li>마무리는 선호</li>
</ul></li>
<li>주제 관련 이슈, 문제점, 걱정거리, 뉴스
<ul>
<li>예시, 상황, 생각, 의견</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
<p><img src="https://cryscham123.github.io/posts/01_projects/opic/notes/img/2025-06-21-14-20-15.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="답변-구조" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="답변-구조">답변 구조</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>main idea
<ul>
<li>첫인상, 요지, hook</li>
</ul></li>
<li>body
<ol type="1">
<li><ul>
<li></li>
</ul></li>
<li>강조 구간 (2-3 문장 속도감 있게)</li>
<li>강조 구간</li>
</ol></li>
<li>conclusion
<ul>
<li>역질문 what about you?</li>
<li>제안하기 why dont we 동사, lets 동사</li>
<li>급 마무리 thats it for this question</li>
<li>1 + 3</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="공부-방법" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="공부-방법">공부 방법</h2>
<p>주제별로 공부</p>
<p>묘사 -&gt; 루틴 -&gt; 비교 -&gt; 과거 경험 -&gt; 롤플레이 -&gt; 어드밴스</p>


</section>

<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> 맨 위로</a> ]]></description>
  <category>영어</category>
  <guid>https://cryscham123.github.io/posts/01_projects/opic/notes/00.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
